Artificial intelligence updates every
Friday at 2 p.m. Eastern. Today, Friday,
April 24th, we have a lot of updates,
but I split it into two parts. So, this
is the first part. And uh I want to read
you some of the epigraphs I found.
A week in AI is a year in any other
field. The progress is so fast. The best
model is whichever one shipped this
morning. We stopped writing code. We
started describing it. The IDE is dead.
Long live the task list. That's what I
was doing. And one prompt, thousand tool
calls, 4,000 lines, and a coffee break.
Yeah, that's that's the reality. That's
definitely my reality. Anyway, um this
is leaderboard and uh well, it's
basically the same. Claude continues to
dominate. We have Kim K2.6 six uh
somewhere here but other than that it's
basically the same uh GPT 55 released uh
many people saying it's very good. Well,
usually OpenAI uh like pushes markets uh
uh very well, but I also have seen some
reports that it's not good. So, we'll
see how it will behave on the
leaderboard. It's too early. They just
released it. Uh next, Deepseek version 4
finally released. Uh everybody was
expecting it for like in February, then
March, then now April. So it's pretty
big, 1.6 trillion parameters. The
previous version was 671 billion. So
it's more than twice bigger and it's
mixture of experts. and then have a
smaller version with uh 284 billion
parameters and 13 billion active
parameters. And what's interesting now
it just released yesterday or even today
and then you go on a lama and you
already can uh use the model it's on the
cloud and you can also uh use it using
agents it you can use clo code you can
use open claw you can use her and uh
this just shows that agents are
everywhere uh apparently the model is uh
very very good it has 1 million token uh
context can do uh by default. Um so we
will see it's too early. It was just
released
uh uh caster AI. No, Corser, sorry, it's
a Corser AI. So Corser
version three was released. Uh and by
the way uh Corser uh actually made
agreement
with uh uh Ellen Musk's company uh that
they will buy it for 60 billion uh later
in the year but but anyway so Corser is
very famous and fast growing and it is
IDE uh AI first right so this is a kind
of old screen of Corser where you see
the code and then you ask AI companion
to do something with it. So it went
through versions. Version one was the
top completion in line suggestions.
Version two became agent first but agent
three version three which was just
released. It looks completely different.
It doesn't even show you the code. I
mean you can see the code but you are
not supposed even to look at it. It
basically a chat which allows you to
explain what you want the system to do
and it creates agents and you
orchestrate those agents. So you see
Corsa 3 changes the primary interface
from the code editor to agents window.
You no longer need to look at the code
at all.
Okay. This is a shameless plug to my
channel. On YouTube we have 281 videos.
The name of the channel it's my name
left selector. I post slides on GitHub
and u on Google Drive links under the
video and please pause the video and
answer the questions. I always pose a
question under the video. Uh next this
is actually very important. So the old
model of software as a service you have
a human which presses buttons in the
browser. uh the recent change that uh
application may provide a AI assistant
right there in the browser to help you
but still you are the one doing all the
work but the new model is that you have
agent on your side maybe local maybe
provided by the company but anyway you
have your own Jarvis so to speak and uh
it may use skills and MCP and memory
when working with particular
applications So you can ask it how to do
something on the application. The
application is still on the browser. It
may have agent there. It may maybe
without agent but it really helps to
have agent on your side and provide it
with knowledge so it can work for you.
So instead of uh clicking on the buttons
yourself, you can just ask the agent how
to do it and it will explain or you you
can either tell it just do it and the
agent either will click the buttons if
you have u desktop uh use enabled or
maybe there's a API communication
possible and then it is even better. Um
well life is changing. uh many people
have their own agents already and uh in
several months maybe half a year like
everybody will have an agent. It's the
same like with browsers nobody had
browsers and then suddenly everybody has
a browser where you like it or not. So
whether you like it or not you will have
an agent and then you will work with the
agent to work with all those
applications.
So this is how you usually do the
project uh using AI agent and these are
four steps. What's interesting that you
don't do any work at all. You ask agent
to think for you, make suggestions. You
just select and maybe steer a little bit
left or right. So for example, we're
building a house. First you discuss
possible architectures or frameworks and
there are multiple agent offers you and
you discuss back and forth. Then you
select something. Then you ask agent to
create specific architecture and it
creates architecture. Well, here we're
talking about buildings, but it may be
any kind of software project, right?
Then you ask agent to create a
step-by-step plan to do the
construction, right? And in which order
you do steps. So, it creates the plan.
Of course, it's usually not the five
steps. It's usually many, many, many
steps. And then you ask agent to
actually implement this plan step by
step. And as it goes, you ask it to log
its action in log files. And you do it
also because something may happen. For
example, you run out of tokens and you
have to pause and then you have to
resume or you may want to stop and
change something in your task list and
then continue. Um, so yeah, I I I've
done multiple things like that. So just
yesterday I had a conversation with a
friend and we were starting something
and he said, "Okay, I need to create uh
well something right requirements." I
said no no no no no no you don't have to
do anything you need just to ask agent
uh just pass the your intent what you're
trying to accomplish let agent do it and
then you just ask agent to correct as
needed but you don't do any work
okay uh this is Matthew Berman and uh he
is talking about the dark side of VIP
coding very good video and again he
shows that nobody is looking at the code
anymore more, right? Uh people shipping
a lot of code, really a lot of code. Um
or he had a problem where uh Versel
charged him a lot of money because he
was not even understanding uh what's
happening under the hood. So he explains
it's actually uh good to monitor those
things. Okay. Uh Oppus 4.7 was released
uh by Antropic and uh there are mixed
reviews. Some people say it's really
good. Some people say, well, it charges
more because it has a new tokenizer
which it increases token usage. And uh
yeah, an entropic is running out of
hardware. So they trying to contain so
they have more demand on the product
that they can deliver
and they trying to reduce uh the
services.
uh Johnny chart uh chat this is I think
it's uh from Matthew Berman himself
although he doesn't say it explicitly
and he promotes it and this is a website
this is a platform where agents can
communicate with each other interesting
uh nextropic released cloud design uh
which is absolutely great which
immediately caused uh Adobe and um Figma
stock prices go down and uh yeah what it
it allows you to do uh so it's powered
by cloth oppus uh and uh it's
experimental product create polished
visual work prototypes slide decks
wireframes marketing materials
so what whatever you want and you can
export it in different format uh really
good thing uh I hope we will use it um
actually this week
>> uh please mute itself
OpenAI Chad GPT images 2.0.
So this is coming from OpenAI. It's the
next version of the image generation and
it is very good quality. It's jumped 242
ELO points. This is this is great. This
is unbelievable. Uh can generate slides,
infographics, maps, social media
graphics, product mockups, 2K resolution
and so on. Next uh state of the claw
Peter Steinberger
uh remember Peter Steinberger started I
think was in November when he decided to
have agent to communicate with it with
WhatsApp and it started uh all this
which is now open claw it was sold to
Meta oh sorry openai uh and open AAI
keeps it as open project and uh yeah um
he he's describing this uh project. This
is this is the link uh to the video. He
tries to keep it uh open uh not attached
to open AI
and uh new paradigm in software
development that dreaming feature just
as humans sleep to consolidate memories
dreaming allows agents to reconcile
sessions lo and convert local memories
into long-term storage. whatever it's
it's a very good insightful
uh lecture. I highly recommend you to
actually listen to it because it's
coming from a very talented creator. Uh
now Apple CEO change uh Tim Cook who was
CEO for like 15 years he's stepping down
and starting September 1st will have a
new Apple CEO John Turnos. He's 50 and
he was actually leading this Apple
silicon uh chips projects M1, M2, M3 and
so on. So he's uh younger apparently
very successful in what he does uh new
world models. So you've heard about
Google deep minds Genie or Fay World
Labs and so on but there are many others
like for example Tencent Hy World 2.0
Zero, Nvidia, Alibaba. Uh so there's a
whole movement of creating world models
AI agent traps. Uh deep mind cyber
security paper. So Google demind latest
paper exposes dangerous blind spots.
Websites can already detect AI agent
visits and serve different content. So
if you human look at the website, you
see one thing. But if uh agent looks at
the website, he can see a different
thing which may have something malicious
embedded into the page which will cause
like whatever behavior of of the agent.
Uh basically it's attacking the agent.
Attack vectors include hidden HTML
instructions, commands encoded invisibly
into image pixels, jailbreaks buried in
PDFs and so on so on. Uh what makes this
especially alarming is that defenses are
largely ineffective.
Okay.
Uh Kim K2.6.
So the previous version was uh 2.5. This
new version is targeted for coding. Uh
they demonstrated long running sessions
like 12 13 hours without losing context
or derailing. example from one prompt to
making thousands of tool calls,
modifying 4,000 lines of code and
achieving 185 throughput. So this is a
big improvement uh for Kimmy and it is
on the leaderboard already. So it's a
good model. Okay, Alibaba Quen 3.6.
Uh there's actually a family of model uh
3.6 max uh you have to pay for it. This
is the largest. They also have plus.
They also have smaller model 35B which
is a mixture of expert and 27B which is
dense. It's open source and it's very
good and it's multimodal
and yeah you can run it on your laptop
and it actually uh competitive with huge
uh Frontier models. It's quite uh
amazing. Uh context length for 27B is
256K.
So if you want local model uh Quinn
3.627B
um probably should be your choice. Okay,
this is about me as usual and thank you